麦克斯 有惊喜要给你 就在你身后
Max, I have a surprise, and it's right behind you.
转身前我想问 是奥普拉来了吗
Before I turn around, is it Oprah?
我会乐死的
'Cause I will die.
是烘焙学校的毕业证
It's a diploma from pastry school.
别闹了 快说到底是什么
No, seriously, what's the surprise?
盖尔我也能接受哦
I'll even take Gayle.
如果不是学校关门 你本来能毕业
You would've graduated if the school hadn't closed,
奥列格刚好认识个办假证的人 所以...
And Oleg knows a guy who fakes documents, so...
你现在是烘焙学校毕业生
You're a pastry school graduate,
而我有房产中介证跟法国公民身份
And I'm a real estate agent and a French citizen.
我可以在法国带人看房子哦
I'll be able to show houses in France.
请问你怎么去法国
And how are you getting there?
我还是个持照飞行员哦
I'm also a licensed pilot.
我不是什么烘焙学校毕业生
Look, I am not a pastry school graduate.
我连高中都没毕业
I'm not even a high school graduate.
我只有从一个"吓弯取直"的课程毕业过
The only thing I graduated from was a Scared Straight Program,
所以我现在不再是"弯"的了
which is why I'm not gay anymore.
麦克斯 你真的高中没毕业吗
Max, you really didn't graduate?
我以前一直以为你说你高中辍学是开玩笑
I always thought you were kidding about dropping out of high school,
就跟你总说霍华德·斯特恩是你老爸
Like when you say that Howard Stern is your dad.
他真的是 看我们眼睛多像[其实没有]
'Cause he is. Look at our eyes.
我也真的辍学了
And I did drop out.
当时我说 "滚吧 傻逼们
I was like, "Later, suckas.
天涯何处无饮水器啊"
I'll find a water fountain somewhere else""
饮水器吗 真恶心
Water fountains? Gross.
在私立学校
In private school,
我们从不弯腰 拿嘴接东西
we never bent down to put our mouths on something
除非那东西[人]有游艇
unless it had a yacht.
老娘当年就不屑高中的那张纸
I didn't need a piece of paper from high school,
也不需要这张假的破纸
and I don't need this fake piece of paper,
因为老娘从不玩假的
because I don't fake things.
除了对做爱时 不懂怎么拉女人头发的男人
except orgasms with guys who don't know
我会假高潮
how to yank hair good.
"还好你有回电
Well, I'm glad you called back,
你个软脚虾"
You slimeball.
太好了
Oh, good.
我醒来发现你不在时 很担心呢
When you weren't here when I woke up, I got worried.
担心到坐着边吃饼干边看《老妈一家》吗
So worried you decided to eat cookies and watch Mama's family?
每个人表达悲痛的方式都不同
We all grieve in our own way.
看来我得让脱衣舞女别来了
Guess I should cancel the strippers.
我今天发现了一件
So I found out something interesting today
跟你有关的趣事哦
that has to do with you.
靠 你知道我在奥兰多干的好事了吗
Aw, crap, you found out what happened in Orlando?
何出此言 你在奥兰多干过啥
Why? What happened in Orlando?
你不会是"睡"了奥兰多迪士尼的米老鼠吧
Don't tell me you slept with Mickey Mouse.
我跟了穿吊带裤的四手指人物"睡"过
Well, I slept with someone With suspenders and four fingers.
我想那应该是米老鼠没错[高飞狗]
I'm assuming it was mickey.
总之 那真是爽到九重天了
Either way, it was heaven.
我发现
Well, I found out
你当年才不是你说的那种狠角色
that you're not the badass you claim to be.
我跟你当年高中的校长聊了
I talked to your old high school Principal,
他说你没毕业的唯一原因
and he said the only reason you didn't graduate
是你缺席了一场历史期末考
is 'cause you failed to show up for one history final.
我的高中还没烧毁吗
My high school's still standing?
看来我当年那烟头弹得不够到位
Guess I didn't flick that cigarette far enough.
你居然敢这么侵犯我的隐私
I cannot believe you'd invade my privacy like that.
侵犯你个屁隐私
Invade your privacy?
你还开着门给你"鸟巢"修枝剪叶呢
You shave your junk with the door open.
那又怎样
So?
开的是家里大门
To the apartment.
或许这个能让你改变主意
Well, maybe you'll change your mind
你当年的历史老师
when you find out that the Principal--
也就是现在的校长 哈克老师
your old history teacher, Mr. Huck--
说你这周五可以回校考试
said you can come back and take the test this Friday,
如果你考过了 就给你发毕业证
and if you pass, you'll get your diploma.
如果是哈克老师 我会把你碎尸万段
If that's Mr. Huck, I will murder your face.
麦克斯 求你别杀我
Max, please don't kill me.
我可以住在这里 但不能死这里
I can live here, but I can't die here.
姑娘们安安
Hey, girls.
我买了谷歌眼镜哦
I got Google glasses.
我现在一边看着你们
See, right now, I'm looking at you
一边在亚马逊上订木薯呢
and ordering tapioca on Amazon.
苏菲 现在不太方便
Now is not a great time, Sophie.
麦克斯在不爽我
Max is upset with me
因为我想帮忙她高中毕业
because I'm trying to help her graduate from high school.
你确定她不爽你不是因为
Aw, you're sure she's just not upset with you
你嚼东西的样子欠揍吗
'cause of the way you chew?
抱歉 我吃东西得嚼是我不对
I'm sorry I have to chew, everyone.
我发现只要麦克斯回老家考一场历史考试
I found out Max can go take one history test in her hometown,
她就能拿到高中毕业证
and then she'll get her diploma.
麦克斯 你知道我一直对这货...
Max, you know I've never been a big fan
没好感
of hers...
但我觉得你能拿到那毕业纸挺好的
But I like the idea of you getting that degree.
像我就永远忘不了
I mean, I'll never live down
没有从那失聪学校毕业的事
not graduating from school for the deaf.
苏菲 你又没有失聪
You're not deaf, Sophie.
是啊 所以读得辛苦啊
I know. It was really hard.
我才不管她是跟谁联络了
Well, I don't care who she called,
反正我绝对不会去
'cause I'm not gonna do it.
如果哈克老师觉得我这辈子
And if Mr. Huck thinks I would ever step foot
有可能再回他装逼的教室里
back in his Mr. Know-it-all university,
我有几个字送他
I have two words for him.
"哈"你妈
"Huck u."
哈克老师早猜到你会这么说了
That's what Mr. Huck said you'd say.
他还说高四那年
He also said that senior year,
你曾兜售过"哈你妈"文化衫
you sold "Huck u" T-shirts
他还说你这个人没追求 没恒心
and that you have no ambition and no follow-through.
听到这里我才确定 他真是你老师
That's when I knew he was really your teacher.
我没追求吗
No ambition?
老娘卖衣服挣来的钱
I made enough off those shirts
让我一个月啥都不用干
to do nothing for, like, a month.
我弄了两张去罗德岛的大巴票
Look, I got two bus tickets to Rhode Island.
我都不知道坐大巴能提前买票呢
I didn't even know you could buy bus tickets ahead of time.
我还以为只要到汽车站 人看起来像
I thought you just showed up, and if you looked like
这辈子犯过足够多的错误 就能上车了
you made enough mistakes in life, they let you on.
去嘛 麦克斯
Come on, Max.
我好久没试过等了这么久 就为了听人说"好"
I haven't waited this long to hear someone say yes
上次还是我在失聪学校时呢
since I was at school for the deaf.
好
Fine.
好吧 我去
Fine, I'll go.
但只是为了证明哈克老师是错的
But only because Mr. Huck thinks I won't.
我就不打扰你们俩读书了
Aw, okay, well, I'm gonna let you two start studying.
我得坦白
And in full disclosure,
在你们俩废话连篇时 我看了点黄片
I watched some porno during this conversation.
再见啦
See ya later.
麦克斯
Hey, Max.
卡洛琳跟我们大伙说了
Caroline told everyone the good news
你要回去考美国历史的好消息了
about you going back to take that American history test.
干得好
Good for you.
是啊 我昨晚开始读书了
Yeah, I started studying last night,
我要代表全体白人
and on behalf of all white people,
向你们黑人为我们所做过的一切道歉
I would like to apologize for everything ever.
我接受你为你们做过的一切道歉
Well, apology accepted for everything ever
除了奴役黑人与开盖璞的事
except for slavery and The Gap.
给 麦克斯 这是我为了要考
Here, Max, I brought you the history book
美国公民考试 在读的美国历史书
which I'm studying from for my citizenship test.
婴儿不是直接能拿公民吗
Aren't babies automatically citizens?
我都不知道我为啥要帮你
I don't know why I root for you.
给 你们国家的历史很丰富啊
Here, your country has a very rich past,
不像我们棒子国 历史都被日本鬼子偷了
unlike Korea, which had its past stolen by the Japanese.
阿憨 有丰富历史的是欧洲历史
Han, we are not talking about European history.
不是美国历史
We are talking about American history.
你这水平 看来只能一辈子当服务员了
Oof, you're going to be working here forever.
姑娘 保重
Good luck, lady.
麦克斯 我想出了个办法
Okay, Max, I've come up with a way
能让你边工作边读书
for you to work and study at the same time,
就跟你边逛街边偷东西一样
Like when you shop and steal at the same time.
是啊 每次他们给我看监视录影带时
I know, when they show it to me on those security cameras,
我总是超佩服自己
I'm always impressed.
我真的没听说过有人会我这招呢
I mean, I really don't know anyone else who's doing it.
麦克斯 上菜 八号桌的玉米煎饼
Max, pick-up. Burrito for table eight.
不是吧 我才刚到
Ugh, jeez, I just walked in.
为啥总有这么多煎饼破事缠着我
Why do I have to have all this burrito drama?
卡洛琳说每次你来拿菜
First, Caroline says I have to quiz you
我都得考你一题 所以...
every time you come to the window, so...
请问热门歌曲《杰西的女朋友》
Who was the sexually virile male pop singer
是哪位爷们流行歌手创作的
responsible for the hit song Jessie's girl?
里克·斯普林菲尔德
Rick springfield.
真聪明 玉米煎饼拿去吧
Burrito's all yours, smarty.
奥列格 不行
Oleg, no.
你得从我给你的问题卡中提问
You have to ask questions from the flash cards I provided.
我用颜色区分了问题的年份
They're color-coordinated by century
再依照当时的总统做了细分
and subdivided by President.
麦克斯 干嘛这么看我
Don't look at me like that, Max.
我不是死书呆好吗 我自学了道基舞呢
I'm a fun person. I taught myself the Dougie.
好 我要问啦
Okay, here goes.
美国宪法第几修正案
Which amendment to the United States constitution
给了女人们...
guarantees a woman's right to...
投票的权利[第19]
vote?
等等 女人可以投票啊
Wait, women can vote?
所以你们说女人可以投票时
So when you say women can vote,
是指除了给《美国偶像》投票之外吗
you mean, like, besides for American Idol?
麦克斯 你自觉不会读书 其实不是
Max, you think you're not smart, but you are.
你只需要想出几招记忆妙方
You just need to come up with little tricks
来帮忙唤醒[慢跑]记忆
to help jog your memory.
我的记忆才不会慢跑
My memory doesn't jog.
我吸过太多大麻 它现在正在某家医院
I've smoked so much pot, it's in one of those hospitals
重新学习怎么走路呢
learning to walk again.
"伟大的妥协"是什么
What was the Great Compromise?
除了让你搬进我家之外的吗
You mean besides you moving in with me?
让美国设了参议院与众议院
It created the two houses of Congress.
下一题 禁止贩卖
Next question: What was the movement
与饮酒的运动叫什么
against the sale or drinking of alcohol called?
大肠运动吗
The bowel movement?
不 是禁酒运动啦
No, the temperance movement.
也别再提厕所了
And don't mention the bathroom.
之前经过那个不知以前产啥的小镇时
I've had to pee since we passed that last town
我就想尿尿了
that used to make something.
那就去上厕所啊
Just go to the bathroom.
你是在怕什么啊
What are you so afraid of?
那厕所啊
The bathroom.
我愿意使用公厕
I will use a public bathroom.
也愿意乘坐公共大巴
I will use a public bus.
但我不愿意使用在公共大巴上的公厕
But I will not use the public bathroom on a public bus.
下一题
Next card.
不要 给我颗糖 我学够多了
No, give me a Twizzler. I know enough.
不许吃糖 认真点读
No candy. Study harder.
你绝对只能拿个"D"了
You're looking at a solid "D."
我的分数得跟我的胸部大小一样啊
Well, my grades should match my boobs.
下一题
Next question. Okay.
美国宪法是在哪个城市诞生的
In what city was the constitution written?
不知道
No idea.
费城吗
Philadelphia?
靠 我差点要回答这个呢
Oh, damn it, I almost said that.
这么明显
It's right there.
费城出产牛肉奶酪三明治
Philadelphia makes cheesesteaks.
宪法很俗气[奶酪]
The constitution is cheesy.
我为什么要质疑自己呢
Why do I doubt myself?
还多远啊
How much further?
我还以为罗德岛只是一个小州呢
I thought Rhode Island was supposed to be a tiny state.
什么时候能下车啊
When are we stopping?
得先经过克兰斯顿 普罗维登斯
Well, we have to pass Cranston, Providence,
然后我们在霍普[希望]下车
and then our stop is Hope.
麦克斯 你是在叫做"希望"的小镇出生的吗
Wait, Max, you were born in a town called "Hope"?
在霍普[希望]之外
Well, just outside hope.
也在成功与金钱之外
and success and money.
好吧 我是没希望了
Well, there's no hope for me.
真憋不住了 我要杀进去了
I have to pee so badly. I'm going in.
把糖留下
Leave the Twizzlers.
给 快读书
Here, study.
天啊
Oh, my God.
你们知道马桶不是装饰物而已吧
You know the toilet isn't just there as a suggestion.
东北高中
Wow, North East high.
从没想过我会再踏足这里
Never thought I'd be here again.
完全没勾起我任何回忆啊
This sure brings back no memories.
挺有爱的
It's cute.
资金不足公立学校风格的那种有爱法
You know, in an underfunded public school kind of way.
等等 你是高中生吗
Wait, are you in high school?
天啊 我简直是千年老妖
Oh, my God, I'm a hundred.
就这里 2C教室
Oh, there it is, 2-C.
等等
Hold on.
为什么你把它们关起来了
Why are you covering those up?
我化学能过都是靠它们的呢
They're the only reason I passed chemistry.
麦克斯·布莱克
Max Black.
哈克老师
Mr. Huck.
我很惊讶
I'm surprised.
惊讶我会来吗
That I showed up?
不 惊讶你还活着
No, that you're alive.
我也有同感 姐妹
You and me both, sister.
想必你就是卡洛琳了
And you must be Caroline.
你看起来就像是
Oh, you look just like the girls
以前会被麦克斯恶整的那种姑娘
Max used to give wedgies to in the cafeteria.
她现在还会呢
Still does.
女士们 他叫赫克托
Oh, ladies, this is Hector.
赫克托今天会跟我们一起考试
Hector will be joining us today,
因为他考试时没有出席
as he was not in attendance during exam day.
哈克老师 我迟到是因为我姐没叫我起床
Ay, yo, Mr. Huck, that's 'cause my sister didn't wake me up
也因为她是个贱人
'cause she's a bitch.
很好
Very good.
这地儿咋这么多小桌子啊
This place is filled with tiny tables, yo.
抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry.
只有老师与小流氓们
It's teachers and delinquents only
可越过此线
beyond this point.
你可以在这里等
You can wait out there.
-你紧张吗 -有一点
- Are you nervous? - A little.
我忘了我包里有大麻烟
I forgot I have a joint in my purse,
我可不想被老师开除啊
and I don't want to get expelled.
麦克斯 你行的
Max, you can do this.
我知道你觉得自己不行
I think you think you can't,
但我知道你能行
but I know that you can.
看着我
Look at me.
你很聪明
You are smart.
你是什么
What are you?
聪明鬼
Smart.
你看 你已经答对一题了
See, you already got one question right.
好了 孩子们
Okay, kids,
开始动脑筋吧[戴上思考之帽]
put on your thinking hats.
我以为在教室不许戴帽子呢
Ay, yo, I thought we couldn't wear hats in the classroom.
这句话我就当没听见
I'm going to ignore that,
否则我会被你蠢哭的
because if I don't, I will weep.
"1775年 保罗·里维尔警告哪两个人
"In 1775, Paul Revere warned which two men
说英国人要来抓他们了"
that the British were coming to arrest them?"
在野兽男孩的歌曲《保罗·里维尔》中
In the Beastie Boys song Paul Revere,
保罗有一匹马和一夸脱啤酒
he had a horsie and a quart of beer.
山姆·亚当斯是啤酒 如果喝太多
Sam Adams is a beer, and if you have too much,
会醉到帮某个叫约翰的陌生男子打飞机
you end up giving a John a hancock.
所以答案是山姆·亚当斯和约翰·汉考克
Sam Adams and John Hancock!
我在等丙肝测试结果时都没这么紧张
I wasn't this nervous when I waited for the results of a hep C test.
反正我也完全没学那玩意
Then again, I didn't study for that one at all.
我觉得我过了
Ay, yo, I think I nailed it.
你挂了 赫克托
You failed, Hector.
真的假的
For real?
是真的
For really real.
就连麦克斯好心
You even got the answer wrong
大声说出来的答案 你都写错了
that Max so graciously said out loud.
没关系啦 哈克老师
Aw, that's cool, Mr. Huck.
再接再厉嘛
Next time, right?
是啊
Sure.
麦克斯 很抱歉
Max, I'm sorry to tell you that...
我不该质疑你的
I was wrong to doubt you.
你的成绩是"B"
You got a "B."
你过了
You passed.
你个爱说谎的死老头
You lying son of a bitch.
是真的 麦克斯
It's true, Max.
老实说 我前后看了三遍
In fact, I went over it three times
以确保不是我发疯
to make sure I wasn't insane.
你那位朋友用来帮你的那些方法
Whatever that friend of yours there did to help you,
的确奏效了
it really worked.
抱歉 但我实在不能在外面站着了
I'm sorry, but I can't stand out there any longer.
不少高一新生得了会对我"起立"敬礼的传染病
I've caused a small pandemic of erections in freshman boys.
我过了 我得了个B
I passed! I got a "B"!
我的分数跟你的咪咪大小一样
Now my grade matches your boobs!
我要拿到我不在乎的
I'm getting that stupid diploma
那个白痴毕业证了
I said I didn't care about.
麦克斯 除了拿学位证 你还可以干别的呢
You can do more than get that diploma, Max.
明天就是毕业典礼 如果你在这过夜
Graduation is tomorrow, and if you stay overnight,
明早可以和同学们一起参加典礼
you can walk with the class in the morning.
好啊
Uh, yes.
你居然想去参加毕业典礼
You want to go to graduation?
你太有我的风范了
That's so me of you.
我一个学渣拿出了学霸的魄力
Well, I busted my "A" to get that "B,"
我当然得享受全套服务啦
and I want to get the whole package.
太好了
That's great.
那我们明早10点见
Well, we'll see you tomorrow at 10:00 A.M.
赫克托 那我们就在你平时让陌生人
And, Hector, we'll see you in front of the Am/Pm
给你买啤酒的那个便利店门口见啦
asking strangers to buy you beer?
床归我 桌子归你
I call the bed. You can have the table.
麦克斯 这床太小了
Max, that bed is so tiny,
咱俩得抱着睡了
we're gonna have to spoon.
这房间唯一有可能出现抱抱的情况
The only spoon that's ever been in this room
是起火后 我们抱着跳出火堆
was hovering over a flame.
这房间蛮可爱的
Well, it's cute.
虽然我来这之前没有打预防疫苗 但
I'm not vaccinated for anything in here, but...
这里蛮可爱的
it's cute.
还很"安全"
And safe.
是啊 这里有有线电视
Yeah, they have cable,
房间也可以按小时租
and you can rent rooms by the hour,
所以我以前经常跟一个叫小麻吉的妓女
so I used to come here to watch Sex and The City
来这里看《欲望都市》
with a prostitute named Tiny Marge.
她会给我带香蕉面包 然后我们一起玩
She'd bring me banana bread and hang out.
真欢乐
It was fun.
这下可好
Oh, great.
这里居然没有咖啡机
There's no coffeemaker.
算了 我找到了
Never mind, found it.
你以前来这里 你妈不会担心吗
Your mom wasn't worried when you'd come down here?
不会啊
No.
她还有点嫉妒 因为
She was a little jealous that I was hanging out
我跟小麻吉玩不带她 但...
with Tiny Marge without her, but...
我妈唯一担心的也只有...她自己
The only thing my mom ever worried about was herself.
她很 自私
She's selfish.
她因为"有事"
She missed my birth
错过了我的出生
'cause she "had a thing."
拜托 她不可能这么糟糕
Come on, she can't be that bad.
而且事实证明 你不算是高中辍学的学渣
Turns out, you're not that big of a high school dropout,
所以你妈可能也不是一个人渣
and she's probably not that big of a monster.
至少她独自抚养你 没把你弄死啊
I mean, she raised you alone, and you didn't die.
其实我都死过两次了
I did actually, twice.
但帮她说句公道话 那两次她都不在
But in fairness to her, she wasn't there either time.
麦克斯 你何不请她来参加你的毕业典礼
Max, why don't you invite her to your graduation?
别告诉我你没她电话
And don't say you don't have her number.
你手机里那个"爬出她洞洞"的联系人就是她
I know it's in your phone under "lady I came out of."
我还知道在你手机里 我的称呼是"屁精"
I also know I'm in your phone as "fart monster."
那是因为我认识三个卡洛琳 要区分
That's because I know, like, three Carolines.
-胡说 -被你发现了
- No, you don't. - Busted.
我来打 你来留口讯
Here, I'll dial, You just leave the message.
-给 -不要
- Here. - No!
-麦克斯 -屁精
- Max! - Fart monster!
听话
Just do it.
明天你看见她一定会很高兴的
You'll be so happy when you see her there tomorrow.
提前是我们能活过今晚
If we live through the night.
是我 麦克斯
Hey, it's me, Max.
那个棕色头发 在你肚子里只住了7个半月
Brown hair, lived in you for 7 1/2 months
就因为你眼瞎不会看香烟盒上的警告
due to your inability to read the warnings
而被赶出来的人
on the side of cigarettes.
听着 明天是我高中毕业典礼
Listen, I'm graduating from high school tomorrow,
如果你不忙着从炉子底下找药片
so if you're not busy looking for pills under the stove
或抓邻居家的猫去换酒钱的话
or selling the neighbor's cat for beer money,
就过来看看吧
why don't you come?
麦克斯
Max!
干嘛 那只是草稿啦
What? That was a first draft.
按3号键 删除 重录
Hit three, delete, rerecord.
是我 麦克斯
Hey, it's me, Max.
明天我要去高中领毕业证
Look, I'm getting my degree tomorrow at the high school.
地点就在你喝酒的那间酒吧
You know, that's the building between the bar you drink at
和你"跳舞"的那间酒吧之间
and the bar you dance at, so...
按3号键 删除 重录
Hit three, delete, rerecord.
我是麦克斯
Hey, it's Max.
明天是我的高中毕业典礼
I'm graduating from high school tomorrow.
时间是早上10点 希望你赏光
If you can make it, it starts at 10:00.
再见
Okay, bye.
瞧 不是很难[硬]吧
See, that wasn't hard.
这床被子是 但打电话不是
This duvet is, but that wasn't.
为什么帽子上就一个流苏穗呢
How come they only give you one of these?
麦克斯 要不你还是别说话了
Okay, Max, maybe don't say anything else,
我怕他们把毕业证收回去
or they'll take your diploma back.
好了 毕业生们 时间到
Okay, graduates, it's time.
大家按字母顺序排队
Everyone line up alphabetically,
出发去礼堂吧
and let's make our way.
恭喜
Oh, and congratulations.
你做到了
You did it.
麦克斯 长袍加身的你看着好聪明呀
Max, you look so smart in that robe.
其实没有啦
I'm not that smart.
我刚发现原来袍子里面是要穿衣服的
I just found out you're supposed to wear clothes under this thing.
麦克斯 我从未问过你
Max, I never asked you.
你离毕业证只差一场考试
You were so close to getting your diploma.
你为什么不去参加呢
Why didn't you take that test?
我本来想去的 但我妈
I was going to, but my mother
那天不让我去上学 非要拉我去逛百货
kept me out of school that day to go to the mall.
在期末考试那天吗
On finals day?
是不是雷文·西蒙尼大驾光临你们的百货
Was there at least a special appearance By Raven-Symone?
有名气的好人不会来这里
No one good ever came here.
就像我妈今天不会来一样
Just like my mother didn't come here today.
还有时间 或许她会来
There's still time. Maybe she'll come.
或许吧
Maybe.
我毕业典礼时 我爸也迟到了
I mean, my dad was late to my graduation
因为他的直升飞机要加油
because his helicopter needed to refuel.
是啊 我妈可能也碰到这种情况了
Yeah, that's probably what happened to my mom.
但她的那架飞"鸡"可能已经睡死在她身上了
But her helicopter's probably passed out on top of her.
我从未像今天这般自信
I have never been more confident,
因为今天我站在这里 看着你们大家
because as I stand here and look out at all of you today...
我以前也是致词的优秀毕业生
I was my class valedictorian.
我意识到 没人可以阻挡我们前进
I realize nobody can stop us.
是啊 我也曾天真如你
Mm-hmm, yeah, I thought that too.
我们就是未来
We are the future.
没错 等10年后你得在大巴上尿尿就梦醒了
Sure we are, until you have to pee on a bus in ten years.
谢谢 艾米
Thank you, Amy.
我"不敢想象"在接下来的4年里
It's hard to imagine not hearing that voice
我每天都听不到这声音了
every day for the next four years.
谢谢
Thank you.
那个 那个 麦克斯的妈妈
Hi, Mrs.--Ms.-- Max's mom.
我是卡洛琳·钱宁 你女儿麦克斯的
This is Caroline Channing, your daughter Max's
好友兼室友兼生意伙伴
best friend and roommate and business partner.
虽然我很不想给你留言
I didn't want to leave this on a voice mail,
但你居然缺席自己女儿的毕业典礼
but I cannot believe you didn't show up
这种行为让我无法理解
to your own daughter's graduation
而且你还是害她当年没能毕业的罪魁祸首
When you are the sole reason she didn't graduate in the first place.
谁会期末考试那天 带女儿去逛百货啊
I mean, who takes their daughter to the mall on finals day?
有你这么当妈的吗
What kind of mother are you?
一直以来我都在麦克斯面前帮你说话
And all the times I've defended you to Max--
我不是在夸自己 但我的确常常
not to make it about me, but it was a lot--
说"她其实没那么糟糕啦"
saying, "She's not that bad. She's not that bad."
但你的确就是这么糟糕 麦克斯说得对
Well, I guess you are that bad. Max is right.
你是个人渣
You are a monster.
如果你已经在路上了 那我们在第2排等你哦
If you're on your way, we're in the second row.
我是金色头发那个
I have blonde hair.
克里斯蒂娜·拜尔斯
Christina Bayers.
那是我孙女
Whoo, that's my granddaughter!
萨拉查·贝尔蒙特
Salazar Belmonte.
那是我儿子
That's my boy!
麦克斯·布莱克
Max Black.
她是我楼下的邻居
That's my downstairs neighbor!
所以你打电话把他们都叫来了
So what, you called them all?
是啊 以防万一嘛
Yeah, you know, just in case.
麦克斯 我错了 你是对的
Max, you were right, and I was wrong.
你妈真的就像你说的那样糟
Your mother's really as bad as you said.
其实没那么坏啦
Mm, oh, it's not that bad.
怎么不是了
What do you mean?
明明是她在期末考试时带你去逛百货
She took you to the mall on finals day.
是啊 但那天是我们过得最开心的一天
Yeah, but it was the greatest day we ever had.
我们买了冰淇淋
We got ice cream,
我们坐在超市的按摩椅上吃
we ate it in the massage chairs at Brookstone,
然后有个小孩掉进喷泉
And then a kid fell in the fountain,
我们都快笑死了
and we died laughing.
哪天都能高中毕业
Well, I guess you can graduate high school any day,
但看到小孩差点淹死
but you can only watch a kid
这种好事可不是天天有
almost drown in a fountain once.
她今天不来没关系
It is okay that she wasn't there today,
因为你来了
because you were.
而且如果没有你推我一把
And none of this would have been possible
这一切都不可能发生
if you hadn't pushed me.
当然如果不是我推了那小孩一把
And that kid wouldn't have almost drowned
他也不会差点淹死
if I hadn't pushed him.
还是稍有区别的吧
Little different.
总而言之 你对我有信心
Bottom line, you had faith in me
就像托马斯·杰斐逊相信路易斯和克拉克一样
like Thomas Jefferson had faith in Lewis and Clark.
天啊
Oh, no.
现在你俩都是死书呆了
Now you're both nerds!